THARAN BALA

Milwaukee, Wisconsin | (414) 243-5462 | tharanbala33@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/tharan-bala/

SUMMARY

With over three years of experience in Full Stack Development, employed Python frameworks, .NET, React.js, Data Science and Cloud technologies to execute numerous projects, delivering results enhancing business performance. Recognized as a proficient decision-maker, a reliable team leader, and possess strong communication skills

EDUCATION

University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Master of Science in Computer Science

August 2022-May 2024

Sri Ramakrishna Engineering College Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science August 2016-May 2020

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Help Desk Chatbot, University of Wisconsin, Milwaukee

February 2024-Present

Built the Help Desk chatbot, an application used as one of the methods of contact for the UWM IT Help Desk with Django,
Rasa framework and using React.js, Typescript, MySQL hosted on AWS

Way Map, Sri Ramakrishna Engineering College, Coimbatore, India

January 2019-May 2019

• Utilizing Unity and Blender, with a focus on C#, implemented an Augmented Reality application suggesting paths to departments throughout the institution

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python (Flask, Django, Pandas, NumPy, Keras, SciPy, TensorFlow, PyTorch), Next.js, .Net, C#, React.js, Typescript, HTML5,

Tailwind CSS, Git

Database: SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB Cloud: Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft Azure

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Supervisor, IT Help Desk

February 2023-May 2024

University of Wisconsin Milwaukee, Milwaukee, WI

Promoted to Supervisor from consultant in 3 months. Oversaw the efficient operation of the Help Desk

Full Stack Engineer Intern

June 2023-August 2023

Seminaut Inc, San Marcos, TX

• Utilized Flask framework to create REST APIs and React.js, Typescript to develop reusable models for a webpage of the company's website, while engaging with fellow interns and maintaining code synchronization through Git version control

Consultant, IT Help Desk

October 2022-February 2023

University of Wisconsin Milwaukee, Milwaukee, WI

- Provided prompt and professional IT support to students, faculty, and staff, addressing a wide range of technical issues and inquiries related to software, hardware, networking, and university systems
- Demonstrated strong problem-solving abilities by troubleshooting and resolving complex technical problems, minimizing downtime and ensuring efficient operations

Software Developer

August 2019-February 2022

Payoda Technologies Pvt Ltd, Coimbatore, India

- Cloth Prediction application(Deep Learning)- Created a Flask and React.js based dashboard to predict cloth stitch type, stitch pattern, hosted the application on AWS, securing a Proof of Concept (POC) project for the company
- Smart Call Centre Designed an application deploying Flask, Vue.js, and NLP to assist Customer Care in handling customers with ease for Verizon, resulting in a Proof of Concept (POC) project for the company
- myTheo Designed features for myTheo, a Real Estate Client with agencies across the USA and headquarters in California, incorporating Ruby on Rails, HAML, and Google Street View, increasing the company's sales by 20%
- Alternative Soft Developed portfolio construction software, processes for institutional investors, utilizing technologies such as .NET, React.js, micro services, and SQL, resulting in a 40% increase in clientele